Guide to the Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Collection, 1973-1998 AIS.2002.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Collection
1973-1998
1982-1996
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee
AIS.2002.02
19.25 Linear Feet (20 boxes and 1 reel of Microfilm)
The Mon Valley Unemployed Committee (MVUC) was established in 1982 as a response to the massive unemployment resulting from the closure of many western Pennsylvania steel mills. The MVUC is a sub-committee of the Unemployed Committee of Southwestern Pennsylvania (USCP), affiliated with the National Unemployed Network (NUN), and a model for the other regional unemployment councils of Pennsylvania. Their records highlight efforts to provide aid to the unemployed through peaceful protesting, lobbying, conferences, and hotline services. Many documents in the collection speak to the inner workings of the organization since they kept meticulous records of meeting minutes, service evaluations, grants, donations, budget proposals, and trips to Washington, D.C.
Related Materials
Denominational Ministry Strategy Collection, AIS.1989.07, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Steffi Domike Papers, AIS.1997.20, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
William C. Frederick Papers, AIS.1999.22, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Previous Citation
Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Collection, 1973-1998, AIS.2002.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Joan Maloy Striegel in 2003 from her father Elmer J. Maloy's collection.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
The contents of the collection are organized into five series:
Series I: Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Administrative Files, 1973-1990
Series II: Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Financial Files, 1979-1993
Series III: Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Legislative Files, 1979-1998
Series IV: Newsletters and Media, 1982-1991
Series V: Unemployment Conference Materials, 1979-1986
History
The Mon Valley Unemployed Committee (MVUC) was formed in 1982 to assist the newly unemployed as a result of the closure of many of the region's steel mills. Following the recession of 1981-1982, the region's steel mills began to outsource their labor in an effort to cut costs. The outsourcing of the region's steel mills devastated the Mon Valley because many of the workers did not have the skills or education to find equally well paying work elsewhere. While the government set up programs, such as the Trade Adjustment Assistance (TAA) to aid workers through subsidizing their education and helping them find new employment, this aid did little to help middle aged and elderly unemployed steelworkers feed their families or pay their mortgage. Also, due to the region's massive influx of unemployed steelworkers, finding any employment became nearly impossible. The stress of unemployment adversely affected the entire community.
Sensing the Mon Valley's need for a localized organization specifically aimed at aiding the Mon Valley's unemployed, the MVUC centralized the organization in McKeesport, Pennsylvania, an area utterly devastated by the closure of US Steel National Tube Works. Two community organizers, Barney Oursler and Paul Lodico, were chosen by the Steering Committee to lead the organization. Funded by the United Way, private donations, and membership dues ($1/year for unemployed, $5/year for employed), the committee set to work establishing a hotline to answer questions ranging from utility shut-offs to day care options while parents looked for work. Aided by local food banks, churches, and shelters, the MVUC became the go to place for navigating the confusion and disorientation that result from long-term unemployment.
While MVUC was able to aid the Mon Valley's unemployed temporarily, Oursler and Lodico realized that unemployment aid lay mostly in the hands of state and national legislators. What began as small trips to downtown Pittsburgh to protest the closure of the Dorothy 6 Steel Mills evolved into busloads of members traveling to Washington, D.C. to lobby Congress to extend TAA benefits and end Welfare Liens. In the early 1990s, the MVUC formed their most effective protest, the Council to Remove Welfare Liens (CRWL), as a response to the ever present threat of liens on the property of the unemployed. MVUC also lobbied for the Pennsylvania Low Income Home Energy Assistance (LIHEAP) funds. The group is still aiding the Mon Valley's unemployed as of 2009.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the MVUC cover the period from 1973 to 1998 with the majority of the documents pertaining to their activities from 1982 to 1996. While the collection contains standard meeting minutes, budgets, bylaws, constitutions, newsletters, and correspondences, it also contains job descriptions and service evaluations. The administrative files exist as a "how-to" guide for forming, operating and maintaining an unemployment agency. Mixed within the legislative files are photographs illustrating the MVUC's trip to Washington, D.C., and lobbying efforts in Downtown Pittsburgh. Many documents in the collection pertain to correspondence between the MVUC and state legislators which showcase the organization's commitment to long term unemployment aid. Barney Oursler and Paul Lodico's notes on conferences hosted by MVUC and meetings attended also re-enforce that commitment. Also present in the collection are media correspondence as well as newspaper clippings by and about the MVUC. Clippings from the Committee's newsletter, Mon News, further details the organization's activities.
Separated Material
Oversize materials located in Range 1/14/3.
Iron and steel workers -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.) -- Political activity; Iron and steel workers -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Steel industry and trade -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Deindustrialization -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Unemployment -- Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); Associations; Labor; Monongahela River Valley (W. Va. and Pa.); McKeesport (Pa.); Allegheny County (Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.); National Unemployment Network (U.S.); Unemployed Council of Southwestern Pennsylvania; Mid Mon Valley Unemployment Committee; Specter, Arlen; Heinz, John; Berenick, Carol; Lodico, Paul; Oursler, Barney; Mon-Valley Unemployed Committee
- Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Administrative Files, 1973-1990; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains documents relating to the administration of the MVUC. The bulk of the collection relates to administrative files from 1983 to1988. Included in the series are hotline statistics specifying the services the organization provided to the unemployed who called the hotline. The majority of the series contains policy council and steering meeting minutes, unemployment resources, and the MVUC bylaws, constitution and mailing lists. The MVUC also retained detailed staff records which includes job descriptions, evaluations of services, and staff brainstorming session notes. The files in this series are organized in chronological order.
  - "Making an Offer We Can't Refuse" Richard K. Harmon, June 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Local 2227 Publicity, USWA Unemployment in 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Unemployment Compensation - Social Services, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - USWA Unemployment Organizing, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Reports on Stress and Unemployment, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Unemployed and Joint Committees of Local 2227 on Overtime, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Unemployment Compensation, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Unemployed Compensation, Legislative Action, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hotline Information, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Utilities Hotline, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - MVUC Handbook Hotline Information, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hotline Referral Forms, February- June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12-17)
  - Information on Reagan and Thornburgh Cuts to Special Education, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letter to President Reagan from Central Labor Union and Industrial Union Council, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Food Bank Information, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hotlines, Methodist Union of Social Agencies, Info, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - History of MVUC, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - History of Unemployment, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Economic Crisis, Unemployed Organization, and Unions (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pamphlet, "Laid Off! Here's Help for You", undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Health Care Petition, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Membership Meetings, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Extended Benefits Campaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Mon Valley Unemployed Steelworkers (MVUS) Campaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - MVUC Campaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - MVUC Campaign Speeches, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Unemployed Committees- Other Locals, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - MVUC Activities, May 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Outreach Campaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Urban League, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Original Letter Drafts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Human Costs of Unemployment", 1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Rally Information, October 6, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - National Unemployed Network (NUN), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Single Family Home Mortgage Assignment Processing Report" by U.S Department of Housing and Urban Development, September 1982, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "The Youth Project", 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Labor Outreach (NUN), July 27, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - MVUC Fliers, Press, and Donor Lists, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - MVUC Hotline Info, Letters, Steering Committee Minutes, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - MVUC Leaflets, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - MVUC Union Affiliations, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Measurement of Unemployment in McKeesport Proposal, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Hotline Information and Resources, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Jobs and Justice Day Notes, June 15, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Foreclosures/Health Care, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Drop-In Center Contact, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Horning's Visit to the Mon Valley, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Unanswered Correspondences, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Unemployment Compensation Survey Results, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Steering Committee Minutes, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Presbyterian Hunger Project, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - National Conference on the Dislocated Worker, April 4-6, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - MVUC Job Descriptions, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - MVUC CHD, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Notes on July 7th Hearing, Retraining, and TRA, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Welfare Organizing, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - MVUC Coordinator Tasks, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Support Neighborhood Action Coalition, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Flyer for "Women of Steel" Documentary (Mon Valley Media), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Political Economics, MVUC Steering Discussions, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - MVUC Research Group, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Organization Brainstorming, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MVUC Open House, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Form Letter on Utilities, December 8, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, December 13, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - By-laws/Memorandums, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Steering Committee Minutes, January 1983-January 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - MVUC Correspondences, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Job Training Partnership Act (JTPA) Daily Activities, Part I, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - JTPA Daily Activities, Part II, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pennsylvania House Financing Act (PHFA)/ Homeowners Emergency Mortgage Assistance Program (HEMAP) Recertification Information, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - MVUC Policy Council Minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Policy Council NUN Letters, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - MVUC Meeting Minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - MVUC Evaluation, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Community Technical Assistance Center (CTAC) Report, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Administrative Committee Reorganization, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - MVUC Administration Brainstorming Notes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Membership Committee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Steering Committee Minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Memorandums, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Renewal Campaign, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Executive Summary, "A Study of Act 75: The Impact of Welfare Reform", June 1984 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - MVUC Community Leaders Election, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "Just Economy" Newsletter, Vol. 2, July-August 1984 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newsletter Monitor, "Community Groups Role on Industrial Policy Debate", September 1984 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Magazine Steel Labor, "Women of Steel" Vol. 49, No. 9, November-December 1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Administrative Resources, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Notes, Pamphlets, and Minutes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Comeback Conference, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Academic Materials, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Activities Reports, October 1984-May 1985 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Issues for Development, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Regional Organizing, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - MVUC Staff Meeting Minutes, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Pamphlets on Mortgages, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mission and Goals, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Carol Bernick Allegations & Responses, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
  - Donor Option Campaign, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
  - Outreach Meeting, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
  - NUN Notes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Bylaws, Constitution, May 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Planning Committee, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Working Group on Community Development Correspondence, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Speech, "Riding the Tiger" by David M. Roderick, Chairman of US Steel Corp., March 13, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Health Care Information Packet, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Information Packets on Health Care, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Helpline Voucher Distribution Pictures, July 17-August 9, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Grievance Committee, October 9, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - MVUC Policy Council/Finance and Administration Meeting, November 22, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Coalition on Block Grants and Human Needs Memo, December 4, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Jobs Impact Bulletin, Vol. 5, No. 16, December 6, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "If You Lose Your Job" Pamphlet, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - "Survival Lessons form the Great Depression" Pamphlet, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - The Mon Valley Renaissance Program of California University of Pennsylvania, Annual Report, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Membership Lists, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - National Consumer Law Center, Inc. Correspondence Concerning U.S. vs. Exxon, July 3, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jobs Impact Bulletin, Unemployment Research Vol. 5, No.12-15, September 13, 1985, November 15, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
  - Magazine, Dollars and Sense, "Displaces Workers: Bearing the Costs of a Changing Economy" No. 110, October 1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Founding Meeting Beaver County Unemployment Committee (BCUC) Pictures, July 30, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Picture of Bill Casey, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Lay-Offs Resource Guide for People in the Mon Valley, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - MVUC Coordinators Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Brainstorming Notes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Objectives and Time Line, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - MVUC Status Reports to CHD, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Constitution, and Charts, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - By-Laws, and Hiring Policies, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Six-Month Goals/Objectives, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Weekly Plans, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Responses to National Unemployed News, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Team Discussion Notes, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Policy Council NUN Letters, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Introduction to MVUC Policy Council, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - MVUC By-Laws/Constitution, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Donor Option Campaign Correspondences, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Policy Council Minutes, January-August, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 43-49)
  - Policy Council Notes on Retreat, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Policy Council Minutes, September-October 1985 (Box 3, Folder 51-52)
  - Policy Council Minutes, December 1985 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Policy Council, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Policy Council Notes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Projects and Proposals, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Grievance Minutes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Presbyterian Hunger Project Proposal, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - United Steelworkers of America, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Save Switch and Brake Coalition, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Job Descriptions and Plant Closing Summary, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors By-Laws, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Notes, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mailing Lists, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Northeast-Midwest Congressional Coalition, US House of Representatives, January 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Pittsburgh Press "No 1 City Still Has Its Hills to Climb", February 23, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Policy Council, April 20, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Steelabor" Vol. 50, "The Changing Situation of Workers and their Unions" No 3, March 1985, Vol. 51, Distressed Communities: The 'Other America' visits Washington (McKeesport, PA) No 2, February 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Information on Job Creation, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - MVUC Policy Council Flyers, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - MVUC Policy Council Minutes, February 23, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - MVUC Policy Council Minutes, June 29, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - MVUC Policy Council Minutes, October 18, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - MMVUC By-Laws, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - MMVUC Policy Council Minutes, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Insurance Applications, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Job with Peace Campaign, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - Jobs and Peace Rally in Washington, D.C., April 20, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - MVUC Staff Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Brainstorming Notes, 1986, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Mailing List, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Activity Reports for 1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Steering Committee Minutes, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Outreach Meeting Minutes, May 4, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Staff Minutes, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Staff Photographs, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Membership Records, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - MVUC Policy Council Minutes, January 13, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Hotline Statistics, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Weekly Staff Activity Sheets, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Staff Activity Logs, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 37-43)
  - Outreach Meetings, May 4, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Membership List, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Policy Council Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Staff Activity Log, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 48-52)
  - Outreach Report Summaries, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - MMVUC Hotline Reports, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - MMVUC Non-Profit Forms, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - MMVUC Outreach Report, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Contact Information, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Policy Council, April 14, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Policy Council, May 19, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Hotline Statistics, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Annual Report, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Greensburg Chapter Material, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - MMVUC Year End Reports, 1988, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Policy Council Materials, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - MMVUC Outreach Report, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - MMVUC Hotline Reports, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Survey Results, January-February 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence County Unemployment Committee (LCUC) Hotline Reports, January-June 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Clarion Works Unemployment Committee (CWUC) Hotline Reports, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - LCUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - LCUC Non-Profit Forms, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - CWUC Outreach Report, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Survey Results, January-March 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hotline Statistics, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Membership Records, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - MMVUC Steering Minutes, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Policy Council Material, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - CWUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - MMVUC Steering Committee Minutes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - MVUC Policy Council Material, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Future of the MMVUC, February 1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Intake Statistics, January-December 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22-33)
  - Policy Council Minutes, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Hotline Statistics, January-December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 35-46)
  - Policy Council Minutes, January 28, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Hotline Statistics, January-September 1993 (Box 5, Folder 48-56)
  - Office Procedures, undated (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Comeback Conference Photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Constitution, undated (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Member Contact Information, undated (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Original Member Mailing List, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Membership List, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Administrative Drafts, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Hotline Names and Addresses, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Mailing List, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Phone Lists, undated (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Proposals, Drafts, and Outlines, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Resources for the Unemployed, undated (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Layoff Resource Guide for People in the Mon Valley, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Steering Committee Minutes, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Steering Committee Legal Issues, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - JTPA Forms, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Members Opinions, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Media Correspondences, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - University of Pittsburgh Correspondences, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - NUN Bylaws and Constitution, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Membership List, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Complete Membership List, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Policy Council Notebooks, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - MVUC Job Descriptions, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Membership Renewal Packets, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Sheriff's Sale" Script, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - MVUC Artifacts: Sweatshirt, Bag and Tools (Oversize 1)
- Mon Valley Unemployed Committee Financial Files, 1979-1993; II.